Sreenadh Madappura

Java Full Stack Developer

Evere, Brussels, Belgium • +32-465271150 • sreenadhm01@gmail.com





m sreenadh-m



sreenadh.dev



sr33nadhm

Fullstack developer with more than 3 years of experience implementing both frontend and backend systems in Java, JavaScript and Typescript; led re-architecture of current platform that plays a critical role in the organization and caters to 100000+ users, increasing efficiency by 20 percent.

SKILLS

Programming Languages - Java, JavaScript

User Interface Development - Angular, React.is, MobX, Material UI, HTML, CSS, iQuery

Backend Development – Java Spring Boot, Node.js, Express.js

Database Management - MySQL, DB2, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

DB middleware – Hibernate, JPA, Knex.js, Objection.js

Test frameworks - jest, junit

Message Queues - RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka

Amazon Web Services - DynamoDB, S3, EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, CloudFront

Google Cloud Platform - Compute Engine, Cloud Storage, BigQuery

Project Management - GIT, JIRA, Bit Bucket, Confluence

DevOps – Docker, Kubernetes, Concourse, Jenkins

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Java Engineer

May 2023 - Present

ASPL BV, Brussels, Belgium

Handling internal applications for the organization including UI development in Angular and backend development in Java Spring Boot, Hibernate and MySQL.

Full Stack Developer

May 2021 - May 2023

IBM India Private Limited, Bangalore, India

Handled IBM internal application UI development in Ext. is and backend development in Java Spring Boot, Hibernate and DB2.

Built and deployed 5+ new features which handle core facilities of the organization subdomain.

- Launched the application changes for organization restructure of the company, by deploying key features which helped to manage 25000+ employees..
- Led the migration and re-architecture of the application to IBM Cloud by modernizing and containerizing the application using **Docker**, **Kubernetes** and **Open Liberty**, increasing the deployment rates to 300%.
- Leading the modernization of the application to Java Spring Boot, reducing the CVE exposure of the application to 0.
- Administering design and code reviews for 3 teams handling 5 projects under the same leadership.

Systems Engineer

August 2019 - May 2021

Infosys Limited, Trivandrum, India

Steered 3 client projects and 1 internal project that cater to 100000+ users, as a full stack web developer. Designed and engineered 10+ applications, programmed scripts in languages like JavaScript and Python.

Client projects include:

Online video platform migration - Brightcove Inc

Handled the position of Full Stack Developer for designing and developing new features and plugins along with a team of 250 members which helped them migrate their content and user information to the target platform.

- Implemented backend applications and more than 22 APIs in Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB.
- Programmed 5+ scripts to assist the migration and data validation of 100000+ records.
- Delivered 25+ UI components using **React**, and integrated with backend, using **REST Api**.

Infosys Internal OTT based project - Infosys Ltd

Commanded the position of Full Stack Developer for Infosys internal project on OTT technology. Designed, developed and deployed 25+ frontend and backend components.

- Engineered backend services with Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA and MongoDB.
- Written and maintained 50+ automated test cases in **jUnit**.
- Collaborated with the UI design team and generated 15+ UI components in Angular.
- Successfully integrated the User Interface with backend services using **REST Api**.
- Actively participated in 100+ code reviews, monitored and ensured coding practices are being followed.

<u>Internet Measurement Platform - Comcast Corporation</u>

Handled the position of Backend Developer for Internet Measurement Platform for this overseas client. Shipped and monitored 10+ new features and scripts.

- Built and screened **Node.js** applications for monitoring internet speeds, using speedtest SDK.
- Developed and maintained a data pipeline using Scala and Kafka.
- Performed data analytics and report generation using Elasticsearch and Kibana.
- Generated scripts in **Python** to process 100000+ **JSON** feeds from **Elasticsearch**

Online video platform - Vuclip

Commanded the position of Full Stack Developer for this Singapore based Video platform. streamlined and regulated 25+ features for their backend services.

- Delivered and remodeled more than 15 **Java Spring Boot, Hibernate** and **MySQL** based microservice backend applications.
- Migrated monolithic billing platform services to microservice architecture
- Onboarded more than 4 payment gateway services to the new billing platform.

EDUCATION

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Mysore, India

Master of Computer Applications — Computer Science

August 2017 - May 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Winter Internship – Infosys Ltd

January 2019 - May 2019

Completed the internship with Infosys in their Global Education Center, Mysore which included training in Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Angular. A Capstone project was implemented and submitted as part of the internship.

Microservices with Java, Spring, Docker, Kubernetes - Udemy

Completed certification course from Udemy for Spring Boot Microservices and their containerization using Docker and Kubernetes.

URL: https://ude.my/UC-95990a70-6e31-44fb-bf87-2852161f0d8f/